tatta ima hajimete kizuita
nijyuuyo jikan kimi kimi kimi
ishiki sezaru o emasen
nanka (nanka) itsumo to chigau
kimi to (futari) gikochinai kaiwa
masaka (ryouomoi) iya kataomoi
yabai shisen acchatta
nani nani kono doki doki
shikoukairo guccha guccha konsen
konna koto hajimete dayo
netsu demo aru no kana
kyuutenchokka irasshatta koigokoro
acchuuma kao hakka de makkakka
ba ba baka na te ga furueruzo
kore ga zoku ni iu koi nano
yayayacchatta kaiwa kami makuri
kimazui chinmoku mamimumemo
kimi no (kimi no) kimochi shiritai yo
kakakata kataomoi
hatsukoi itsumo no tsuugakuro
pika pika hikaru I do fall in love
sora mo tobesou sa
kakakata kataomoi
たった今 初めて気づいた
恋に落ちたのだな～
24h キミ☆ キミ☆ キミ☆
意識せざるをえません!
なんか (なんか) いつもと違う
キミと (二人) ぎこちない会話
まさか (両思い) いや 片思い
やばい! 視線合っちゃった!
なになに?! このドキドキ?!
思考回路 ぐっちゃぐっちゃ 混線・・・
こんなこと 初めてだよ
熱でもあるのかな～
急転直下 いらっしゃった 恋心
あっちゅうま 顔 発火で まっかっか
バ・バ・バカな?! 手が震えるぞ
これが 俗に言う 「恋」 なの?!
やややっちゃった 会話 噛みまくり
気まずい沈黙 マミムメモ
キミの (キミの) 気持ち 知りたいよ
カカカタ☆カタオモイ
初恋! いつもの通学路
ピカピカ光る I do fall in love!
空も飛べそうさ
カカカタ☆カタオモイ
I just realised it for the first time
That I had fallen in love~
Twenty-four hours a day thinking of you you and nothing more than you!
It's something I wasn't consciously aware of
Somehow (somehow) I'm feeling different from the usual
With you (the two of us) and our dull chatter
Don't tell me (mutual love?) Nope it's a one-sided crush
This is bad! Our gazes met!
What what? Why is my heart pounding like this?
Did a short circuit just make a mess out of my mind?
This is my first time... feeling like this...
I wonder if I have a fever~
Suddenly and precipitately love has arrived.
Instantly igniting my face into a bright red
T-That's stupid?! My hands are shaking
Is this really what they call "love"?
I-I did it! A conversation filled with stutters
This awkward silence... *mumble mumble*{not really sure bout this... need a better version for the mamimumemo which seems to be blabbling to break the silence}
Your... (Your...) I want to know your feelings.
O-One-sided love
First love! The usual way to school
The shining light. I do fall in love!
I feel I could fly towards the sky
O-One-sided love
asa okite hao migai te
attoiuma gogo juu ji
kyou mo takusan waratta naa
takusan tokimeita naa
tomodachi to baka mitai ni sawai deru toki ni mo
chirachiratte me ga au
guuzen dayo ne
hatsukoi nante ie nai
kyara janai n da mon
nee ashita mo aeru yo ne
mabuta o tojiru to
kirakira kimi darake
kyou mo tanoshikatta ne
aa koi shite n da naa
ureshii na ureshii na
hajimemashite koi gokoro
ashita mata aeru ne
oyasuminasai
yume de sugu aeru ne
朝起きて 歯を磨いて
あっという間 午後10時
今日も たくさん 笑ったなぁ
たくさん ときめいたなぁ
友達と バカみたいに騒いでる 時にも
チラチラって 目が合う
…偶然、だよね。
初恋なんて言えない
キャラじゃないんだもんっ!
ねえ あしたも会えるよね?
まぶたを 閉じると
キラキラ キミだらけ
今日も 楽しかったね
あー 恋 してんだなぁ
うれしいな うれしいな
はじめまして こいごころ
あした また あえるね
おやすみなさい
ゆめで すぐ あえるね
Woke up in the morning brushed my teeth
In the blink of an eye it's 10pm
Today we laughed a whole lot
We had a great time
At times with my friends acting like fools being noisy
Fluttering our eyes met.
It's a coincidence right?
I wouldn't call this my first love
It's not my character.
Say will we be able to meet again tomorrow?
As my eyelids close
I see you sparkling all over the place
Today was fun too wasn't it?
I'm in love~
So happy so happy
It is my pleasure to meet you my new-found love.
Surely we'll meet again tomorrow~
Have a good night
We'll meet immediately in our dreams
So have a good night
Narration   Katsura Reiko
Motivation
Shinonome Institute
Nichijou 01
Kokeshi
Akabeko
Salmon
Tokisada Prefectural High School
Wonderful
Nichijou 02
Nichijou 03
{\fad(00)\blur0\fs88\b1\c&H343233&\fnNever Say Never\pos(976.8226.2)\iclip(m 1041 147 l 1041 199 974 233 896 204 914 153 934 173 968 170)}Squid
{\fad(00)\blur0\fs88\b1\c&H343233&\fnNever Say Never\pos(975229.1)\iclip(m 1041 147 l 1041 199 974 233 896 204 903 160 939 197 959 168)}Squid
{\fad(00)\blur0\fs88\b1\c&H343233&\fnNever Say Never\pos(978.4230.7)\iclip(m 1041 147 l 1100 178 1099 211 1069 216 969 239 945 213 957 158)}Squid
{\fad(00)\blur0\fs88\b1\c&H343233&\fnNever Say Never\pos(980229.305)\iclip(m 991 141 l 1036 137 1066 141 1069 216 951 219 951 175 976 170)}Squid
{\fad(00)\blur0\fs88\b1\c&H343233&\fnNever Say Never\pos(980228.38)\iclip(m 991 141 l 1036 137 1066 141 1069 216 954 198 951 175 976 170)}Squid
{\fad(00)\blur0\fs88\b1\c&H343233&\fnNever Say Never\pos(979.8227.8)\iclip(m 991 141 l 1036 137 1066 218 988 214 977 169 954 209 952 171)}Squid
{\fad(00)\blur0\fs88\b1\c&H343233&\fnNever Say Never\pos(979229.6)\iclip(m 1001 139 l 1051 138 1066 218 990 218 989 166)}Squid
{\fad(00)\blur0\fs88\b1\c&H343233&\fnNever Say Never\pos(978.9230.4)\iclip(m 1001 139 l 1051 138 1066 218 1001 215 1001 159)}Squid
{\fad(00)\blur0\fs88\b1\c&H343233&\fnNever Say Never\pos(978.6230)\iclip(m 1001 139 l 1051 138 1066 218 1006 213 1001 159)}Squid
{\fad(00)\blur0\fs88\b1\c&H343233&\fnNever Say Never\pos(979.8228.1)\iclip(m 1025 163 l 1051 138 1066 218 1005 214 1003 180)}Squid
{\fad(00)\blur0\fs88\b1\c&H343233&\fnNever Say Never\pos(978.3229.4)\iclip(m 1025 163 l 1051 138 1066 218 1005 214 1003 180)}Squid
{\fad(00)\blur0\fs88\b1\c&H343233&\fnNever Say Never\pos(978.3228.3)\iclip(m 1025 163 l 1051 138 1066 218 1005 214 1014 173)}Squid
{\fad(00)\blur0\fs88\b1\c&H343233&\fnNever Say Never\pos(978.4230.4)\iclip(m 1025 163 l 1051 138 1066 218 1011 221 1012 170)}Squid
{\fad(00)\blur0\fs88\b1\c&H343233&\fnNever Say Never\pos(979.6231.6)\iclip(m 1049 191 l 1066 218 1011 221 1011 169)}Squid
{\fad(00)\blur0\fs88\b1\c&H343233&\fnNever Say Never\pos(978.6232.2)\iclip(m 1034 213 l 1011 220 1012 169 1028 165)}Squid
{\fad(00)\blur0\fs88\b1\c&H343233&\fnNever Say Never\pos(978.4231.8)\iclip(m 1034 213 l 1011 220 1013 194 1033 190)}Squid
Squid
Fire Alarm
Push Hard
Button
Important Matters and Things to be done
Nichijou 04
Shinonome Institute
What's wrong Yukko?
I can't summon the motivation to do anything.
What are you talking about?
We're high school students you know.
It's the start of a new term.
Motivation is something that comes out naturally once you start doing it.
The motivation to do something before actually doing it won't come out.
How do I get motivated to do
something before I actually start doing it?
The motivation to do something before actually doing it?
Hm...
Anyway just do it!
All right!
I just want to stay as a simple-minded idiot.
Professor! It's about time you woke up.
And... there!
Good morning...
What are you doing?
Today's breakfast will be fried fish.
Eh?!
I want omelette-rice!
Didn't you have that yesterday?
Fish contain lots of nutrients you know!
Stop being picky and eat everything
otherwise you won't grow bigger- Ah!
Um that's our important breakfast so...
Ah no it's not like that!
This isn't anything robotic at all!
Um this is...
Ah it ran away.
Wait up!
Have a safe trip.
Perhaps that cat is also having a hard time?
Ah I'm gonna crash!
Mio-chan selamat pagi!
TL note: Indonesian for "good morning".
Ah Yukko good morning!
What should I do I forgot to bring my student ID...
Huh?
She ignored my selamat pagi?
I won't be called upon by the seniors right?
If that happens
saying "I'm a third year student!" should be enough don't you think?
That won't solve anything.
What?
Thunder?
Even though the weather's clear?
It might suddenly start pouring down you know!
A shower or a hailstorm...
A kokeshi came down.
A-Are you all right Yukko?
Who would've thought that a kokeshi would come down?
What a surprise!
I wonder where it fell from...
I don't know...
But it's extremely unlikely that you'd get hit by a kokeshi in your lifetime!
Those people are rare you know.
I don't think they exist.
It might actually mean that luck is with me!
Luck is not with me...
Yukko are you okay?
An Akabeko of all things...
Akabeko...
I'm wrong it's not that luck is not with me.
We should just think of it this way Mio-chan...
I should be happy that I wasn't hit by raw food.
Thinking like that the small mercy amongst the misfortune-
It's a salmon!
Morning!
Good morning.
Ah Mai-chan good morning.
Selamat pagi!
Morning.
What are you reading Mai-chan?
A real estate information magazine.
Eh?
You're moving Mai-chan?
Undecided.
Do you even say selamat pagi?
It can't be helped I guess I'll let the phrase rest for today.
Yukko.
Selamat malam.
TL note: Indonesian for "good evening".
Mai-chan you should say selamat pagi there!
What language is that?
H-Homeroom will begin.
Um when I came to school this morning this was in the shoe rack...
Did anyone put this in there?
U-Um... If there is anyone who knows about it please tell me okay?
Mio-chan I wonder who did that?
Maybe it's a prank?
It might be something unexpected
like a student who likes the teacher...
I don't think they would leave a Maitreya statue though.
But well it's not like I don't understand
people who have unachievable aspirations.
Yeah it's that right?
Like the way you feel about Sasahara-senpai.
Y-You idiot!
Where am I?
I have to get home!
I'm sure the professor is worried
and leaving her with the charcoal stove is dangerous.
Eh?
I can't get off!
My chopsticks are gone!
One of my shoes is gone as well!
What should I do?!
My hand's gone!
Now it'll be exposed that I am a robot!
Here it goes.
Thank you for the food.
If you don't finish up quick the bell for fifth period will ring.
Huh?
You didn't like sausages?
Saving the most delicious food for last in a lunch box is fundamental.
Then I can finish by saying: "It's delicious".
Well then here goes... I'm going to eat it!
It came out!
Not yet!
It's over!
Not just yet!
One...
...two...
...three.
Safe!
You're out!
No way Mio-chan!
It's the three-second rule the three-second rule.
No you were already out way before that!
It's delicious!
Yukko really is an idiot.
First comes rock next comes paper rockscispaper doesn't count
rock paper scissors!
Yes!
Good morning everyone.
Spring has come and a new year has started
but the cold days are still continuing.
In my case I have it twice as cold as everyone else.
Anyway make sure you don't catch a cold...
This is a promise with your principal okay?
If you don't listen then I'll be...
...transferred to a different school on principle!
Mio-chan Mio-chan.
What?
He'll get mad if you talk.
Say doesn't the principal notice that his jokes are way too old?
He must know best of all that his jokes aren't received very well.
I wonder about that...
Could it be that he knows his jokes aren't received well
and is putting on a show of even more
effort to the young people nowadays?!
If that's true then this principal...
...is pretty skilful!
Mai-chan?!
Mai-chan is...?!
Could it be because of that old man gag?
Above that this is the first time I've ever seen her laughing so hard!
All right!
This should do it!
Mai-chan!
Why is it?
If I said it here now I feel like I'll lose everything.
Yukko.
Sorry.
Never mind actually.
I guess until she notices...
...I won't grab it.
Well then next is a talk about student guidance from Sakurai-sensei.
Sakurai-sensei please.
Um Sakurai-sensei?
Yes!
I'm sorry I'm Sakurai from student counselling...
I'm sorry... Eh ah...
I get really nervous when there's so many people.
No good this is no good!
I can't always stand and look like a helpless teacher...
I have to say what I need to say properly!
I know!
Do you often see a goat on the school grounds lately?
Let's not take goats with us to the school grounds!
What's wrong...
What's wrong with goats?!
Going to school on a goat isn't prohibited by the school rules
am I right?!
Eh ah... that is...
Mio-chan isn't that Sasahara-senpai?
Eh really?
No... I'll permit goats!
It's rejected rejected!
Absolutely rejected!
There's no way it's okay to bring a goat to school!
You can say that but Tachibana Misato...
Why must I rush about on my own two legs?
First of all the heir of the Sasahara family...
What's that about the heir of the Sasahara family?
You guys are just normal farmers!
So?
What's wrong with the heir saying he's the heir?
Heh so Sasahara-kun's family are farmers.
I feel like I've been deceived.
So that goat at the bike rack was Sasahara-senpai's.
Riding a white goat Sasahara-senpai will come and pick me up!
A happy new year!
M-Me too!
Mio-chan!
Using a cellphone while riding a bicycle is very dangerous
let's stop doing that!
And also one last thing...
This morning a Maitreya statue was in my shoe locker!
I don't think these kind of pranks are good.
Excuse us passing through...
A Maitreya statue.
Mai-chan!
Don't stop suddenly!
Ah this thing again?
It might be déjà vu.
Who did it?!
I won't get mad so raise your hand!
You'll all stay here until he comes forth!
Who was it?
You go forth.
I'm sorry I heard it was Sakurai-sensei's birthday so...
I see a Maitreya statue is no good eh?
With good intentions on your birthday a present.
I'll imagine that you don't need a Maitreya statue.
The principal.
With this the morning assembly is finished.
Thank you very much for your work up until today Principal.
Deputy principal?!
This fire hydrant button has a really strong magical pull that makes you want to press it doesn't it?
Indeed.
What if you try pressing it?
The alarm didn't go off last time I pressed it.
Eh?
Really?
Fire?
No way!
What should we do?
Are we going to run?
Everyone!
For now let's go to the court!
What are you pushing me aside for?!
You're the one pushing me!
What're you saying?
Besides I've always hated you!
Stop it!
We might end up dying here!
Let's get out of here first!
Leave the arguing for later!
Um...
I'm sorry but what is "KY"?{add TL Note: "KY" is short for "Kuukiyomenai" in Japanese which mean "not considering the situation." iken: more literally unable to read the atmosphere.}
TL Note: "KY" is short for "Kuuki Yomenai" meaning "unable to read the atmosphere".
Um...
What could "KY" be?
I'm sorry please tell me about "KY"!
Help me someone!
Hey!
Oh Captain... What could "KY" be?
It's referring to you.
Second grade Class B Sasahara Koujirou.
Please come to the staff room immediately to Tomioka.
It's true it's not violating the school rules... But a goat?
Can't you do something about it?
If you don't like to walk
you could come by bicycle... Just as long as it's not a goat.
Sir.
It's Tomioka.
Tomioka.
Add sensei to it.
Sensei.
Can you call him Sasahara Kojirou and not goat?
He is a goat for now.
My name is Shinonome Nano.
I'm a robot created by Professor whom I live with.
Professor seems to be doing some kind of research
and is at home all day.
I spend my days while also helping out the professor.
Professor!
I warmed up the milk-
I don't have any special features but it seems like I can still feel pain.
Nano what's wrong?
Professor!
My little toe...!
My little toe was...!
Y-Your l-little toe was...!
With this you should be fine for now.
Eh?!
I don't have any special features
but it seems like you can take off my little toe.
Professor what's this key for?
I didn't turn it?
Ah yes it turns sometimes.
You turn it like this.
Ah what's going on?!
I'm sorry I'm full of special features.
See it's something interesting isn't it?
Could it be that you made the key just for this?
Yup.
Could it be that you made the key just for this?!
Yup!
Take it off please!
No way!
Eh?!
Because it's cute.
Remove it from my back please!
Eh... But it's cute...
I want to be more normal.
I want to sit on a chair like a normal person
and turn over when I sleep.
With this I can't even go to school.
I would've been okay with not being a human-type robot at all.
Nano...
I-It's just a lie!
A lie!
Don't take it seriously Professor!
Then take it... {iken: corrected. Over here it sounds like hakase will remove the key. But two lines down it's a different meaning with the some starting words.}
Eh?
Go and win the Akutagawa Award for Literature!
Why?!
Win the Akutagawa Award!
Every day is like that.
Where am I?
Hello!
This is Nano-chan's big toe!
My capacity is one gigabyte.
I would've preferred to be a bit bigger...
The next episode of Nichijou is episode two.
Please look forward to it!